[
    {
        "question": "What is the code name of the project to build four Visakhapatnam class guided missile destroyers for the India Navy?",
        "options": [
            "Project 75 ",
            "Project 15 B  ",
            "Project 17 A ",
            "Project 75 A "
        ],
        "answer": "Project 15 B  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "The recently commissioned Indian Navy\u2019s INS Shivalik stealth frigate is being developed under which Project of the Indian Navy?",
        "options": [
            "Project 17A ",
            "Project 15A ",
            "Project 75B ",
            "Project 75A "
        ],
        "answer": "Project 17A ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the last submarine to be built under Project 75 of the Indian Navy?",
        "options": [
            "INS Vagir ",
            "INS Vela ",
            "INS Khanderi ",
            "INS Vagsheer "
        ],
        "answer": "INS Vagsheer ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Larsen & Toubro launched which multi-purpose vessel (MPV) for the Indian Navy?",
        "options": [
            "INS Samarth ",
            "INS Utkarsh ",
            "INS Surat ",
            "INS Vagsheer "
        ],
        "answer": "INS Utkarsh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following is the India's first private satellite network?",
        "options": [
            "VIDYUDNET ",
            "ERNET ",
            "RAILNET ",
            "PIXXEL "
        ],
        "answer": "PIXXEL ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the headquarters of the newly established Turmeric Board of India?",
        "options": [
            "Kochi, Kerala ",
            "Byadagi, Karnataka  ",
            "Puttady, Kerala ",
            "Nizamabad, Telangana "
        ],
        "answer": "Nizamabad, Telangana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the first chairperson of the newly established Turmeric Board of India?",
        "options": [
            "Abusaleh Shariff ",
            "Ravinder Kaur ",
            "Vinod K Duggal ",
            "Palle Ganga Reddy "
        ],
        "answer": "Palle Ganga Reddy ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under which ministry of the government of India the Turmeric Board of India has been set up?",
        "options": [
            "Ministry of Commerce and Industry ",
            "Ministry of Chemicals and Fertilizers ",
            "Ministry of Agriculture & Farmers Welfare ",
            "Ministry of Micro, Small and Medium Enterprises "
        ],
        "answer": "Ministry of Commerce and Industry ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country is the largest producer, consumer, and exporter of Turmeric in the world?",
        "options": [
            "China ",
            "Indonesia  ",
            "India ",
            "Russia "
        ],
        "answer": "India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which spice is called the Indian Saffron or Golden Spice?",
        "options": [
            "Turmeric ",
            "Coriander ",
            "Fenugreek ",
            "Cumin "
        ],
        "answer": "Turmeric ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which organisation organsied Akhand Bharat Seminar on the occasion of its 150th foundation day and where neighboring countries were invited?",
        "options": [
            "National Centre for Medium-Range Weather Forecasting ",
            "Indian Institute of Tropical Meteorology ",
            "National Meteorological Service provider ",
            "Indian Meteorological Department "
        ],
        "answer": "Indian Meteorological Department ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements are correct regarding PM Surya Ghar Muft Bijli Yojana?  1.It provides subsidies for installing rooftop solar panels for residential houses and using solar energy for electricity.  2.Any Indian citizen with a valid electricity connection and a suitable rooftop is eligible to apply for the PM Surya Ghar Muft Bijli Yojana.  3.The government subsidy will cover up to 40% of the cost of installation of the solar panels.  4.Another key benefit of the PM Surya Ghar Muft Bijli Yojana is subsidized housing loans.  Select the correct answer using the codes given below:",
        "options": [
            "1 and 3 only ",
            "1, 2 and 3 only ",
            "1, 2 and 4 only ",
            "1 and 4 only "
        ],
        "answer": "1, 2 and 3 only ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following have joined the Global Lighthouse Network of the World Economic Forum for transforming manufacturing through innovation?",
        "options": [
            "CEAT and Hindustan Unilever  ",
            "MRF and Dabur ",
            "Michelin and ITC ",
            "Goodyear and Britannia  "
        ],
        "answer": "CEAT and Hindustan Unilever  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Centre for Development of Telematics (C-DOT) has signed an agreement with which Institute for the development of \"Building Blocks for THz Communication Front Ends\"for 6G under the Telecom Technology Development Fund (TTDF)?",
        "options": [
            "IIT Madras  ",
            "IIT Bombay  ",
            "IIT Delhi  ",
            "IIT Kanpur "
        ],
        "answer": "IIT Delhi  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which financial services arm has raised $400 million through its maiden international bond carrying an interest rate of 5.38 per cent?",
        "options": [
            "Bajaj Finance Ltd ",
            "JIO Financial Services Ltd ",
            "Power Finance Corporation Limited D) Tata Capital Ltd "
        ],
        "answer": "Unknown",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is the co-founder and CEO of Dunzo app?",
        "options": [
            "Kabeer Biswas ",
            "Kunal Bahl ",
            "Rohit Bansal ",
            "Binny Bansal "
        ],
        "answer": "Kabeer Biswas ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reliance Power has planned to invest over Rs 10,000 crore in a solar plant and an integrated solar manufacturing facility in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Kerala  ",
            "Telangana  ",
            "Andhra Pradesh  ",
            "Karnataka "
        ],
        "answer": "Andhra Pradesh  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Adani Road Transport has become the highest bidder to manage a 124-km stretch of National Highway 38 in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Karnataka  ",
            "Tamil Nadu  ",
            "Kerala  ",
            "Telangana "
        ],
        "answer": "Tamil Nadu  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which companies has tied up with the Indian Institute of Science (IISc) for setting up a medical school on the IISc Bengaluru campus?",
        "options": [
            "Tata Group ",
            "Reliance industries  ",
            "Adani Group  ",
            "Wipro technologies "
        ],
        "answer": "Tata Group ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Purulia observatory, recently in news, is located in:",
        "options": [
            "Tamil Nadu ",
            "Uttarakhand ",
            "Ladakh ",
            "West Bengal "
        ],
        "answer": "West Bengal ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is developing the National Maritime Museum Complex project in the country?",
        "options": [
            "Union Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Waterways ",
            "Ministry of Agriculture & Farmers Welfare ",
            "Ministry of Rural Development ",
            "Ministry of Housing and Urban Affairs "
        ],
        "answer": "Union Ministry of Ports, Shipping and Waterways ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where is the National Maritime Museum Complex being set up?",
        "options": [
            "Lothal, Gujarat ",
            "Kalibangan, Rajasthan  ",
            "Dholavira, Gujarat  ",
            "Surkotada, Gujarat "
        ],
        "answer": "Lothal, Gujarat ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Gaan-Ngai' 2025 festival is being organized in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Manipur ",
            "Assam ",
            "Meghalaya "
        ],
        "answer": "Manipur ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nawaf Salam has been appointed as the new Prime Minister of which country?",
        "options": [
            "Qatar ",
            "Lebanon ",
            "Kuwait  ",
            "Bahrain "
        ],
        "answer": "Lebanon ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has been appointed as the chairman of the newly-formed Athletes Commission of Athletics Federation of India (AFI)?",
        "options": [
            "Neeraj Chopra ",
            "Bajrang Punia ",
            "PT Usha ",
            "Anju Bobby George "
        ],
        "answer": "Anju Bobby George ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian company has launched India\u2019s first private hyperspectral imaging satellite constellation named Firefly?",
        "options": [
            "Resourcesat ",
            "GalaxEye Space ",
            "Pixxel ",
            "Antrix Corporation "
        ],
        "answer": "Pixxel ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian company has launched the world\u2019s first commercial satellite for surveillance of space objects orbiting the Earth?",
        "options": [
            "AgniKul Cosmos ",
            "Dhruva Space ",
            "Skyroot Aerospace ",
            "Digantara "
        ],
        "answer": "Digantara ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which company launched the satellite of Pixxel and Digantara\u2019s satellite in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Blue Origin ",
            "Virgin Galactic ",
            "Axiom Space ",
            "SpaceX "
        ],
        "answer": "SpaceX ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many persons can an investor declare as nominees under the revised SEBI rules for demat accounts or mutual fund folios?",
        "options": [
            "10 persons ",
            "15 persons ",
            "20 persons ",
            "25 persons "
        ],
        "answer": "10 persons ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has entered into a strategic partnership with ITC Ltd to help startups in the manufacturing sector?",
        "options": [
            "DPIIT ",
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "NPCI ",
            "chatbot to help investors of the securities ",
            "to Rs 10 lakhs from the "
        ],
        "answer": "DPIIT ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Kappad beach and Chal beach have recently received Blue Flag Certification. Both the beaches are situated in which Indian state or UT?",
        "options": [
            "Andaman & Nicobar ",
            "Lakshadweep ",
            "Kerala  ",
            "Puducherry "
        ],
        "answer": "Kerala  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank is spearheading the State Level Bankers\u2019 Committee (SLBC) initiatives for Maha Kumbh Mela 2025 by offering AI-driven customer support, forex transaction facilities, onsite ATMs, and coin vending machines?",
        "options": [
            "initiatives for Maha Kumbh ",
            "Bank of Baroda ",
            "HDFC Bank  ",
            "Kotak Mahindra Bank  ",
            "State Bank of India "
        ],
        "answer": "initiatives for Maha Kumbh ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which state the Department of Science and Technology, Government of India has established its first astronomical observatory of the Eastern region of the country?",
        "options": [
            "Odisha  ",
            "Kerala  ",
            "West Bengal  ",
            "Madhya Pradesh ",
            "have expanded their longstanding ",
            "has introduced \u2018Aditi\u2019, a GenAI-powered virtual relationship manager, to ",
            "has launched the BoB Earth Green Term Deposit Scheme, aimed at raising ",
            "said the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) has decided to waive the \u20b95 crore penalty ",
            "has raised \u20b95,000 crore through the issuance of long-term infrastructure bonds ",
            "\u27a2 Founded : 1908 "
        ],
        "answer": "West Bengal  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the recently inaugurated sixth astronomical observatory set up under the Department of Science, Government of India?",
        "options": [
            "Satyendra Nath Bose Astronomical Observatory ",
            "Kodaikanal Solar Observatory  ",
            "Gauribidanuru Radio Observatory ",
            "Vainu Bappu Observatory "
        ],
        "answer": "Satyendra Nath Bose Astronomical Observatory ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "How much is Bank of India planning to raise through its first dollar syndicated loan since 2012?",
        "options": [
            "$100 million ",
            "$200 million ",
            "$300 million ",
            "$400 million "
        ],
        "answer": "$400 million ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]